PHILIP CUNNELL

Software Engineer

JavaScript developer since 2016. Professional frontend experience in Angular, React, and Vue, and backend experience using Python, Node.js, and very little Java. I have a diverse background in technology industries, including journey analytics at ClickFox, retail music tracks at Beatport, solar energy measurement at eGauge, and automotive finance at Autopay.

philip.cunnell@colorado.edu (908) 812-2395 Denver, CO 80030 www.linkedin.com/in/philip-cunnell/

WORK HISTORY

Full Stack Developer

AutoPay

Denver, Colorado Jun 2022 - Feb 2024

- Enhance efficiency for users applying for various types of car loans by by re-architecting the back and front-end systems.
- Saving developer cycles and measurable amounts of money for the company through the implementation of internal 'Retool' applications. With thorough documentation we were able to empower non technical teams with onboarding new clients into our system.
- Our team's processes set the standard for others to emulate. We refined workflows and tickets, conducted stand-up
 meetings, implemented documentation for processes, upheld testing standards, monitored logs, conducted regular code
 reviews, and actively engaged in technical developer syncs to discuss new approaches to complex problems.

Software Engineer

eGauge Systems

Boulder, Colorado Jun 2021 - Apr 2022

Addressed bugs and integrated features in the primary web app, including distributor location with Leaflet.js.
 Introduced a Python-centric role, deploying a new process via Ansible and gaining introductory system administration skills with eGauge architecture.

Software Engineer

Beatport

Denver, Colorado Dec 2019 - Jun 2021

- Managed feature maintenance, creation, and third-party plugin integration across 5 repositories (e.g., HubSpot, Recurly, FB Pixel, Google Analytics, Exact Target).
- Quickly acquired Python and Django ORM proficiency, adding numerous endpoints and features to the code base.
- Ensured stringent code standards through thorough code reviews and maintained approximately 90% testing coverage across projects.
- Assisted in sprint task organization and occasionally led retrospective meetings.

UI Developer

ClickFox, DBA Bryter

Denver, Colorado Jun 2017 - Dec 2019

- Maintained Front End codebase with Angular 2.x using state management.
- Created and maintained unique sankey diagrams with javascript.
- Tested and delivered work in sprint cycles.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Immersive - Galvanize

Denver, CO Oct 2016 - Apr 2017

BA, Geophysics - University of Colorado, Boulder

Boulder, CO 2008 - 2013

Accomplishments

- Patent System and method to discover and quantify principal driving factors or 'Dominant paths' in interconnected journey data (3/8/2018 - "US 62/640,728").
- Hackathon 'Captain hack the planet' 8 hour team project combining 24 hour rain data mapped to piano notes.

Skills

React Vue.js Angular 2.x Node.js PostgreSQL Python/Django Cypress Jest Mocha Sumo Logic Sentry Retool Contentful